Hello friends, my name is Jai Sharma and
you are welcome to our
[sangeet].
Now friends, let's talk about brother, if
we buy a car, petrol and
you know how high the charges are for petrol,
how much has been increased in its price,
so if you
want to install CNG in your car there, then how much will it
cost. Now first of all let's talk about
third party, so friends, whenever we
take a third party policy and
we want to add CNG in the policy,
suppose you got the policy done today,
after four months of getting the policy done today, you get CNG
added in your car, then how much will it
cost now, friends, the third
party rate of CNG is ₹0, wherever you
live in India,
you have to pay only ₹18 plus GST,
after that
your cost of adding CNG comes to around ₹72-75, so
whichever agent you have got the policy from,
whichever company you have got the policy from, either
email that company or
send it to that agent, from that company
which is your  You have got your CNG RC updated.
Before updating it in the insurance, it should
also be updated in the RC, only then your
CNG will be able to be updated in the insurance.
If the RC is not updated, then there may be a
little problem in updating the CNG in the insurance,
but if you have
bills, if you have taken
proper bills for the CG you have installed, then
sometimes companies update it even by showing the bills,
so if we are getting it updated in the third party policy, then
your expense will be
0 plus GST on it, so this has been
discussed about the third party, now let's talk about the
first party, friends, if you want to update
your CNG that you have taken in the first party insurance, the
CNG that you have installed in your vehicle, then the
first expense that comes for it is
₹, why will it cost 0, because the
third party is included in the
comprehensive policy or first party or
zero day policy that you take, so the
first
third party expense will be ₹
With the third party, after that comes the matter
of first party, so in first party, suppose
you have installed CNG for Rs. 40000,
now in that Rs. 0000, that Rs. 0000 is not just the amount,
that Rs. 0000 is also the ID of your CNG, it is
also the insured declared value. Now
as soon as we update that bill in our policy, if we
put it in the policy, then
we have to enter the CNG ID there as per
that bill,
if the value of your I bill is Rs.
40000,
then we will have to keep the IDV as 40000 only.
Now suppose your
vehicle ID was also of Rs. ₹ lakh, here you got
CNG installed for Rs. 40000, so now your total
vehicle ID also becomes Rs. 40000,
so Rs. 40000 gets added there, if
suppose your vehicle gets stolen or
catches fire  If there is a total loss or
even at the time of claim, the company pays you the claim up to your
IDV which is 340000.
Now
how much will it cost to install it? Now suppose it is
0000, then whatever your cost is, the
company
charges you 0 for that cost plus 4% of that cost for the third party.
Now suppose you have CNG of 00.
In whichever state you
live in India, the rules are same for everyone. The
rate of CNG is not different in any state.
If you drive a private car or
use a private car, then there
you have to pay 4% of the value of your CNG.
Now if the value of your CNG is 40000,
there your 4% becomes 00, then ₹1 becomes
your CNG, ₹0 becomes your third party
's, then ₹1.60 plus tax on it plus
GST of 18%. That much amount you have to
pay to that company at the time of updating the CNG.
So as soon as you apply for this amount, there are
a couple of companies
that update your CNG in your insurance without taking a photo of your vehicle or inspecting it. However, most
companies
ask you to get your vehicle inspected. You
can either do the inspection yourself or get it done through your agent.
If someone comes for an inspection,
he takes a photo of the vehicle and leaves. As soon as you get an
update from the company
that the pre-inspection of your vehicle has been
completed, the company
sends you a link for payment of ₹1.60
plus GST.
I am telling you this tentative amount; it may be
different for everyone. If the value of your vehicle's
CNG is ₹60,000, then
you will have to pay ₹4 accordingly. However,
if the value is ₹0,000, then
you will have to pay ₹4 there as well.  The
amount for each may vary.
After the inspection, you will receive this link.
After receiving the link, you will make the payment using it.
24 hours after making the payment,
your CNG will be updated on your vehicle's insurance.
Now,
after the CNG is updated, if a claim is made for
theft or your vehicle catches fire, the company will pay you the full
amount. It will be the value of your vehicle
plus the value of the CNG.
In case of a fire, a total loss, or theft, the company will
pay you the full amount.
So friends, this was my video on
how to update the CNG in your vehicle and
how to update it in your documents. Do let
us know how you liked this video. If you have
any suggestions or complaints,
you can ask us by commenting in our comments section.
Apart from this, if you liked the video, please
like it, subscribe to our channel,
and if you feel
that the video is helpful, you can
also share it with your friends and in your groups.
[Music]
Thank you